Register to The Kay Swift Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Programs, Publicity, and Clippings, 1930-1986; Series VI; 1' (2 boxes)
  This series is divided into four subseries: A. Programs involving Kay Swift; B. Programs involving others; C. Press releases and publicity; D. Clippings. Subseries A and B are arranged alphabetically by title. Photocopies of three programs of Fine and Dandy (22/628) have been added to the original donation of the papers. Subseries C is also arranged by title, while the clippings in Subseries D are arranged chronologically by year, with undated clippings at the end. All clippings have been photocopied onto acid-free paper, and the originals have been discarded.
  - Programs Involving Kay Swift, VI.A
    - Alma Mater, No date; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 627)
    - Fine and Dandy, 1930; 3 items. (Box 22, Folder 628)
      All photocopies
      1. Week beginning Sept. 15
      2. Week beginning Oct. 6
      3. Week beginning Nov. 24
    - Garrick Gaieties, [1930]; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 629)
    - Golden Decade of Song: The Tuneful Thirties, 1984; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 630)
    - One Little Girl, 1960; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 631)
    - Paris '90, 1952; 3 items. (Box 22, Folder 632)
    - Radio City Music Hall, 1935; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 633)
    - Sondheim and Swift, 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 634)
      No date
  - Programs Involving Others, VI.B
    - An Evening with Gershwin, 1983; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 635)
    - Black Broadway, 1980; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 636)
    - By George, No date; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 637)
    - Carnegie Hall, 1959; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 638)
    - Catholic Dramatic Oratorio Society, 1907; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 639)
      Third annual performance
    - Classical Theatre of China, 1958; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 640)
    - Cleveland Orchestra Summer Pops Concert, 1972; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 641)
    - Confession Stone, 1960; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 642)
      Note inlaid
    - Celebrating the Gershwins, 1982; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 643)
    - Dinny and the Witches, [1960?]; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 644)
    - George Gershwin Memorial Concert, 1937; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 645)
    - The Gershwin Years, 1971; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 646)
    - Kansas City Philharmonic, 1973; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 647)
    - Lyrics by Ira Gershwin, No date; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 648)
    - Major Barbara, 1957; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 649)
    - Mohawk Trail Concerts, 1978; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 650)
    - Tribute to Dorothy Fields, 1970; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 651)
    - Where the Music Is, No date; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 652)
  - Press Releases/Publicity, VI.C
    - Billboard, 1958 (Box 23, Folder 653)
    - Chappell, 1951
      Variety magazine
    - Fine and Dandy--the Music of Kay Swift, No date
    - The Gershwin Years, 1971
    - Hunter's Moon, 1958
    - Original Sound of "The Twenties", [1965?]
    - Reaching for the Brass Ring, No date
  - Clippings, VI.D
    - 1928-1935 (Box 23, Folder 654)
    - 1936-1949 (Box 23, Folder 655)
    - 1950-1954 (Box 23, Folder 656)
    - 1955-1959 (Box 23, Folder 657)
    - 1960-1969 (Box 23, Folder 658)
    - 1970-1976 (Box 23, Folder 659)
    - 1976 (Box 23, Folder 660)
    - 1983-1986 (Box 23, Folder 661)
    - Undated (Box 23, Folder 662)
- Biographical Materials, 1897-1993; Series VII; .25' (.5 box)
  This series includes biographical materials relating to Kay Swift and to others. Subseries A contains biographies written by Kay Swift herself, published information, and miscellaneous items.
  - Biographical Materials Relating to Kay Swift, VII.A
    - Birth certificate (photo), 1897; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 663)
    - Biographies, 1897; 26 items. (Box 23, Folder 664)
      Includes corrected copies.
    - ASCAP, 4 items. (Box 23, Folder 665)
      - Almanac, 1962
        re: The Little Show
      - List of Members, 1963/1978
      - Play Back, 1993 (Summer)
        Quarterly containing Kay Swift's obituary.
    - Swift family tree, [1993?]; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 666)
  - Biographical Materials Relating to Others, VII.B
    - Galloway, Hunter, No date; 2 items. (Box 23, Folder 667)
      (1 incomplete).
    - Stern, Alfred, No date; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 668)
    - Waldron, Charles King, No date; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 669)
- Photos and Drawings, 1915-1984; Series VIII
  This series contains photos and drawings of Kay Swift and others. The 154 photos have been numbered and arranged into three subdivisions: Kay Swift alone, Kay Swift with others, and other subjects without Kay Swift. Persons are identified whenever possible.
  - Drawings
    - Caricature of Kay Swift, Aug 24 1939; 1 (Box 23, Folder 670)
      Micheal Angelo Mustang at the Ringside Bar
    - Caricature of Kay Swift, 1951 Jan. 14; 1 (Box 23, Folder 670)
      Executed in Boston during previews of Paris '90
    - Sketches by Alfred Stern, 4 (Box 23, Folder 671)
  - Photos - Kay Swift Alone
    - Photos - Kay Swift Alone, 1-8 (Box 23, Folder 672)
    - Photos - Kay Swift Alone, 9-19 (Box 23, Folder 673)
    - Photos - Kay Swift Alone, 20-30 (Box 23, Folder 674)
    - Photos - Kay Swift Alone, 31-36 (Box 23, Folder 675)
    - Photos - Kay Swift Alone, 37-45 (Box 24, Folder 676)
    - Photos - Kay Swift Alone, 46 (Box 24, Folder 677)
    - Photos - Kay Swift Alone, 47-194 (Box 24, Folder 678)
  - Photos - Kay Swift with Others
    - Bolcom, William, 195-197 (Box 24, Folder 679)
      (195-196 with Joan Morris, 197 with unidentified)
    - Daughters Andrea, April and Kay, 198-205 (Box 24, Folder 679)
      (202 with stepfather John Dorr, 205 with B. Levin)
      See also Merkin Hall Concert (241)
    - Eubie Blake, 206-208 (Box 24, Folder 679)
      (208 with Billy Taylor)
    - Carlyle, Louise, 209-210 (Box 24, Folder 680)
      210 at Sardie's Restaurant with unidentified
      See also Merkin Hall Concert (237)
    - Comden, Betty, Adolph Green and unidentified, 211 (Box 24, Folder 680)
    - Dorr, John (stepfather)
      See 203
    - Gagliano great-grandchildren
      See Merin Hall Concert (240)
    - Galloway, Hunter, 212-214, 278-280 (Box 24, Folder 680)
      (211 and 212 with 3 unidentified)
      213, 278 on wedding day
      278-280 are color transparencies
    - Gershwin, George, 215 (Box 24, Folder 680)
      At Bydale
    - Gershwin, Ira and 2 unidentified, 216 (Box 24, Folder 680)
    - Holmes, Celeste
      See Merkin Hall concert (238)
    - Hubbard, Faye, 217-219 (Box 24, Folder 680)
    - Jablonski, Edward
      See Merkin Hall Concert (239)
    - Junior Week, Feb. 1914, 220 (Box 24, Folder 680)
      28 students (names on photo)
    - Kaufman, John (grandson), 221 (Box 24, Folder 681)
    - Robert Kimball party (1975), 222-235 (Box 24, Folder 681)
      Includes Eubie Blake, Louise Carlyle, Bobby Short and Katharine Weber
    - Kolster, Bill and 2 unidentified (1946 Oct. 26), 236 (Box 24, Folder 682)
      Signed
    - Merkin Hall Concert (1986 October 14), 237-241 (Box 24, Folder 682)
      Includes daughters Andrea, April and Kay, Celeste Holmes, Gagliano great-grandchildren, and Edward Jablonski
    - Mielziner Leo, and Kenneth Simpson, 242 (Box 24, Folder 682)
      In George Bernard Shaw's The Man of Destiny (copy in 27/726)
    - Paris '90 party, 243-253 (Box 24, Folder 683)
      4 with Kay Swift
      Persons unidentified
    - Oregon, 254 (Box 24, Folder 684)
      Includes Ed Booth, Walter McCoin and Tom Peterson
    - Simon, Al, 255-256 (Box 24, Folder 684)
      (255 with 2 unidentified)
      256 signed by photographer Erik Nielsen (1984)
    - Song writers, 257 (Box 24, Folder 684)
      Jule Styne, Burton Lane, Charles Strouse, Jerry Herman, Betty Comden, Adolph Green, Henry Krieger, Marvin Hamlisch and 8 unidentified
    - Stanley, Minerva, 258 (Box 24, Folder 684)
      On wedding day to Hunter Galloway
    - Swift, Samuel (brother), 259-261 (Box 24, Folder 684)
      See also 270
    - Samuel Swift and Ellen Mary Faulkner Swift (parents), 262-267 (Box 24, Folder 685)
      Includes brother Samuel and unidentified family members
    - Tapper, Bertha Feiring, 296 (Box 24, Folder 687)
      Tapper with her piano students, including Pauline Mallet-Prevost, Leo Ornstein, and Claire Reis
    - Veltin School Reunion, 268 (Box 24, Folder 685)
      Class of 1915
      All unidentified
    - Warburg, James P., 269-270 (Box 24, Folder 685)
      (270 also with brother Samuel)
    - Wayne, John, 271-272 (Box 24, Folder 685)
    - Weber, Katharine (granddaughter), 273 (Box 24, Folder 685)
      See also 230 and 231
    - Weber, Lucy Swift (great-granddaughter), 274-275 (Box 24, Folder 685)
    - Unidentified persons, 276-277, 281-292 (Box 24, Folder 686)
  - Photos - Others
    - Daughters Andrea, April and Kay, 293 (Box 24, Folder 687)
    - Daughters Andrea, April and Kay, 294 (Box 27, Folder 726)
    - Dorr, John Van Nostram, 295 (Box 24, Folder 687)
    - Faulker, 297 (Box 24, Folder 687)
    - Faulker, Ronald (1915 June), 298 (Box 24, Folder 687)
    - Faulkner, Roy (paternal uncle), 299 (Box 24, Folder 687)
    - Fine and Dandy (300 and 301 with Joe Cook), 300-303 (Box 24, Folder 687)
    - Galloway, Hunter (304 with parents, 305 wedding day), 304-305 (Box 24, Folder 687)
    - Gagliano, April Warburg (daughter), 306 (Box 24, Folder 687)
    - Gagliano, April Warburg (daughter), 307 (Box 27, Folder 726)
    - Gershwin, George, Ira Gershwin and 26 unidentified persons (June 1926), 308 (Box 24, Folder 687)
    - Gershwin manuscripts, 309-335 (Box 24, Folder 688)
    - Hubbard, Faye (includes Hubbard's daughters Pat and Joe, Kay Swift's brother Sam, Eldon McCoin, George Peterson, Bob Maynard, and unidentified), 336-341 (Box 24, Folder 689)
    - Jay's Cottages (Elko, Nevada), 342-348 (Box 24, Folder 689)
      Person unidentified
    - Jessye, Eva and Dr. James A. Staudifer (1973), 349 (Box 24, Folder 689)
    - Kaufman, Andrea Warburg (daughter), 350-356 (Box 24, Folder 690)
    - Kaufman, Andrea Warburg (daughter), 357-358 (Box 27, Folder 726)
    - Levin, Betsy and Rachel (granddaughters), 359 (Box 24, Folder 690)
    - Levin, Kay Warburg, 360 (Box 27, Folder 726)
    - Never a Dull Moment (with Irene Dunne and Fred MacMurray, 361-369 (Box 24, Folder 691)
    - Oregon, 370-375 (Box 24, Folder 692)
    - Paris '90 marquee, 376 (Box 24, Folder 692)
    - Pat, 377 (Box 24, Folder 692)
    - Sanderson, Ivan, 378 (Box 24, Folder 692)
    - Skinner, Cornelia Otis, 379 (Box 24, Folder 692)
    - Swift, Joseph (paternal grandfather), 380 (Box 24, Folder 692)
    - Swift, Samuel (brother), 381-382 (Box 24, Folder 692)
    - Swift, Samuel and Ellen Mary Faulkner (parents), 383-394 (Box 24, Folder 693)
    - Teheran conference, 395 (Box 25, Folder 694)
      F.D.R., Churchill, Stalin, General Marshall and 6 unidentified persons
    - Van Nostram, Abigail, 396 (Box 25, Folder 694)
    - Warburg, James P., 397 (Box 25, Folder 694)
      Wedding pose
    - Weber, Katharine Kaufman (400 with brother John), 398-400 (Box 25, Folder 694)
    - Unidentified persons, 401-405 (Box 25, Folder 694)
- Miscellaneous Items, Series IX; .5' (1 box)
  The disparate items in this series are arranged by descriptive headings or proper names. Related materials are housed together.
  - Action for a divorce (Box 25, Folder 695)
  - Address books and loose pages (Box 25, Folder 696-697)
  - American Society of Composers, Authors and Publishers (ASCAP) (Box 25, Folder 698)
    Forty-fifth annual dinner seating list and autographed invitation
  - Appraisal of the estate of Margaret S. Lewisohn (Box 25, Folder 698)
  - Blake, Eubie (Box 25, Folder 698)
    Autograph on record advertisement
  - Century 21 Exposition (1962 Seattle World's Fair) (Box 25, Folder 699)
    Informational packet
  - Church of Truth (Divine Science) (Box 25, Folder 700-701)
  - Galloway, Hunter (Box 25, Folder 702)
    Miscellaneous items
  - Gershwin related material (Box 25, Folder 703)
    - Acrostic by Irving Caesar
    - Benefit (Nov. 1971)
    - Celebrating the Gershwins: A Selected Discography
    - Fascinatin' Gershwin
    - Fragments (p. 7 only) of article
    - Gala rehearsal schedule
    - "A Gershwin Evening" guest list re: Great Performances
    - Hand print
    - List of posthumous material
    - Who's who of cast for play about George Gershwin
  - Independence Home Coming Celebration (Box 25, Folder 704)
    Program and general information
  - Institute of the American Musical (Box 25, Folder 705)
    Chronology of events
  - International Certificates of Vaccination (Box 25, Folder 705)
  - re: last wishes (Kay Swift) (Box 25, Folder 705)
  - List of theatre programs, London, 1958 (Box 25, Folder 705)
  - Passport numbers (Kay Swift and Hunter Galloway) (Box 25, Folder 705)
  - Poems (Box 25, Folder 705)
  - Quotes (Box 25, Folder 705)
  - re: recording project (Box 25, Folder 706)
  - Social Security Numbers (Kay Swift and Hunter Galloway) (Box 25, Folder 707)
  - Stephen Foster Memorial (Box 25, Folder 708)
  - Television Booking Corporation (Box 25, Folder 709)
  - Unidentified notes and miscellaneous (Box 25, Folder 710)
  - West Virginia Centennial, [1959?] (Box 25, Folder 711)
    Organizational, Program and Financial Information
- Sound Recordings, Video Recordings, and Film, Series X
  Sound recordings, video recordings, and film have been transferred to the Historical Sound Recordings Collection in the Music Library. For further information about archival recordings and film relating to Kay Swift, please contact the Curator of Historical Sound Recordings.
- Music from the Radio City Music Hall Archives, 1935-1936; Addendum 1; .5' (1 box)
  This series consists of photocopies of music by Kay Swift from the Archives of Radio City Music Hall. The music dates from Swift's tenure as a staff composer at Radio City during the years 1935 and 1936. Included are both music newly-composed for Radio City and arrangements of songs which were also used in Swift's other theatrical projects.
  The music is arranged in the order it was received from Radio City. The four-digit numbers stamped on the original scores, reproduced on the photocopies, and transcribed in the register represent the numbering system in the Radio City Archives. Whenever dates appear they indicate the presence of pages photocopied from the program for that week's Radio City production.
  All materials in this addendum to the Kay Swift Papers were provided to the Yale University Music Library through a special contractual agreement with Radio City Music Hall Productions. The Radio City materials may be used for scholarship and research; however, all other uses must be cleared through Radio City.
  - Fine and Dandy (Box 28, Folder 727)
    [812]
  - Fine and Dandy (Box 28, Folder 728)
    1319
  - Fine and Dandy (Box 28, Folder 729)
  - Sunny (Box 28, Folder 730)
  - Sunny (Box 28, Folder 731)
  - Roxyettes (Box 28, Folder 732)
  - Sunny (Box 28, Folder 733)
  - Up Among the Chimney Pots (Box 28, Folder 734)
    2015
  - Professor, How Could You?, February 21, 1935 (Box 28, Folder 735)
    2829
  - Collegiate Number (Box 28, Folder 736)
    2831
  - Forever and a Day (Box 28, Folder 737)
    2840
  - Forever and a Day, February 28, 1935 (Box 28, Folder 738)
    2841
  - Forever and a Day (Box 28, Folder 739)
  - Forever and a Day (Box 28, Folder 740)
  - Interlude (Box 28, Folder 741)
    2842
  - Waltz for Ballet (Box 28, Folder 742)
  - Forever and a Day (Box 28, Folder 743)
  - Physical Culture, April 4, 1935 (Box 28, Folder 744)
    2865
  - Masseur Incident (Box 28, Folder 745)
  - March for Rockettes (Box 28, Folder 746)
    2866
  - March for Rockettes (Box 28, Folder 747)
  - Intro to "There's Gold", April 11, 1935 (Box 28, Folder 748)
    2871
  - There's Gold in Them Thar Hills (Box 28, Folder 749)
    2872
  - There's Gold in Them Thar Hills (Box 28, Folder 750)
  - There's Gold in Them Thar Hills (Box 28, Folder 751)
    2873
  - Intro and Typewriter Interlude (Box 28, Folder 752)
    2890
  - Headlines, May 9, 1935 (Box 28, Folder 753)
    2901
  - Young Man of Manhattan (Box 28, Folder 754)
    2904
  - I Gotta Take My Hat Off to You (Box 28, Folder 755)
    2954
  - Black and White (Box 28, Folder 756)
    2963
  - Black and White (Box 28, Folder 757)
    2964
  - Black and White (Box 28, Folder 758)
  - Black and White (Box 28, Folder 759)
    2965
  - I Gotta Take My Hat Off to You, June 20, 1935 (Box 28, Folder 760)
    2966
  - Black and White (Box 28, Folder 761)
    2967
  - Overture #3, Coney by the Sea, July 25, 1935 (Box 28, Folder 762)
    3016
  - Overture #3, Coney by the Sea (Box 28, Folder 763)
  - Coney by the Sea (Box 28, Folder 764)
    3020
  - Sawing a Woman in Half (Box 28, Folder 765)
    3031
  - Up Among the Chimney Pots (Box 28, Folder 766)
    3032
  - Chimney Tops Routine (Box 28, Folder 767)
    3033
  - Chimney Tops Routine (Box 28, Folder 768)
    3034
  - Footnotes From The Greek (Box 28, Folder 769)
    3065
  - Blonde or Brunette, August 29, 1935 (Box 28, Folder 770)
    3079
  - Blonde or Brunette (Box 28, Folder 771)
  - Prologue to Blonde or Brunette (Box 28, Folder 772)
  - Blonde or Brunette (Box 28, Folder 773)
  - Blonde or Brunette (Box 28, Folder 774)
  - Blonde or Brunette (Box 28, Folder 775)
  - Blonde or Brunette (Box 28, Folder 776)
  - Blonde or Brunette (Box 28, Folder 777)
    3080
  - We've Got a Ticket for the Sweepstakes, September 19, 1935 (Box 28, Folder 778)
    3095
  - Road Show [lyrics only] (Box 28, Folder 779)
    3101
  - Road Show (Box 28, Folder 780)
  - Road Show (Box 28, Folder 781)
  - Road Show (Box 28, Folder 782)
  - Road Show (Box 28, Folder 783)
  - The Little Church Around the Corner, September 26, 1935 (Box 28, Folder 784)
    3104
  - The Little Church Around the Corner (Box 28, Folder 785)
    3105
  - The Little Church Around the Corner (Box 28, Folder 786)
    3106
  - Church - Ballet #4 and Glee Club (Box 28, Folder 787)
    3107
  - Ballet # 2 "Waltz for a Dancer" (Box 28, Folder 788)
    3108
  - I'm All Washed Up in Love (Box 28, Folder 789)
    3139
  - I'm All Washed Up in Love (Box 28, Folder 790)
    3141
  - Put It Down On Paper, October 31, 1935 (Box 28, Folder 791)
    3151
  - Sawing a Woman in Half (Box 28, Folder 792)
    3165
  - Sawing a Woman in Half (Box 28, Folder 793)
    3166
  - At the Golden Calf, December 30, 1935 (Box 28, Folder 794)
    3216
  - The Golden Calf (Box 28, Folder 795)
    3220
  - The Golden Calf (Box 28, Folder 796)
    3221
  - The Wooden Horse of Troy, March 13, 1936 (Box 28, Folder 797)
    3299
  - Graduating Gibson Girls (Box 28, Folder 798)
    3304
  - Polka - "Staccato" - Graduating Gibson Girls (Box 28, Folder 799)
  - Graduating Gibson Girls (Box 28, Folder 800)
  - Graduating Gibson Girls (Box 28, Folder 801)
  - Graduating Gibson Girls (Box 28, Folder 802)
  - Graduating Gibson Girls, March 26, 1936 (Box 28, Folder 803)
  - Graduating Gibson Girls (Box 28, Folder 804)
  - The Little Church Around the Corner (Box 28, Folder 805)
    3441
  - Fine and Dandy (Box 28, Folder 806)
    3805